Yo, welcome back to another ad direct full ad sequence tutorial.
My name is Adam,
and today we're gonna be checking out U G C content or user generated content.
So right now I'm going to be looking at a winning ad sequence.
I'm gonna go through this sequence with you, but first off,
we're gonna check out how we came up with this idea and we are gonna go
through scripting, creating shot lists, um,
all the way through to actually shooting the ad.
And finally on the backend at the post-production
actually structuring the ad itself and how we can create different
variations of that exact same ad so that we could scale it,
we can figure out what our audience is reacting to the most,
what is getting the best click-through rates and ultimately getting the best
sales. So yeah, I'm excited to take you through this.
And yeah, so this product right here,
or this brand is called Grip Harness. It's a harness for a dog.
I'll just, uh, show you this.
So right here you can see the Grip Harness. Um,
first off, let's take a look at how we came up with the idea. Now,
we've worked on these ads before in the past, over the years,
so we've got kind of a good idea with what works and what doesn't work.
And in the past we've really focused on like the easy on and off of
this product, this harness for the dog.
And that's kind of worked.
But what we've figured out lately is that our,
the audience are really reacting and we're getting way better retention
on the video ads themselves when there is a lot more emotion involved
in the ad.
So let me just bring up the website so I can give you an idea
of what one, what I'm talking about. So if I just make this full screen,
so first off, right here,
we've got no more pulling takes three seconds to put on and off.
So the emotional side of this would be no more pulling,
it's the actual experience of the dog being walked.
Is that dog enjoying that pulling? Is the dog owner
enjoying that?
That moment of being pulled by the dog is the whole entire
experience of walking the dog an enjoyable experience.
Something that really is a heartfelt thing with a lot of dog owners.
So what we want to write off, first off,
we see happy smiley faces, happy smiley dog,
and yeah, that's kind of the vibe that we want to be going with.
We wanna be pulling on heartstrings. Uh,
right here we've got some bullet point
Like,
Like benefits and features of this product.
So it is easy on and off in three seconds, eliminates choking and pulling.
So that's a good pain point there. Personalized name and phone number,
so it's good for security, et cetera. Um,
we figured out that's not really one of the biggest selling points,
so we'll include that, but a little bit later on in the ad.
And then we've got reduces risk of neck injury, tracheal collapse.
So that's the actual safety of the dog.
So that's a really great one to be focusing on for like a pain point because it
really focuses on the emotional side of, is my dog really happy?
Is my dog safe When we're out walking, is it having,
is my dog having the best experience when we go out walking?
So we really wanna be focusing on like figuring out these things and figuring
out what our viewers are gonna be thinking about when they're out walking their
dogs, right? Or this relates to any sort of product,
but right now we're focusing on the, yeah,
the emotional side of walking your dog.
And then we've also got the free exchange and 60 money back,
60 day money back guarantee,
and we can kind of fit that in in like different ads here and there.
That's not really one of the biggest things, but again,
it's a good thing to put because it's, it's a good selling point.
So right up here it says here, 50% off free shipping, et cetera.
So these are all things that we can use within our ads. Uh,
let's scroll down. Makes walking your dog so much easier.
Um, okay, I am just looking at the fonts here and the text.
So we've got lots of different highlights and um, yeah,
bold fonts and et cetera.
So they're using a lot of grays and oranges and whites in
on this page.
So these are all things that I'm gonna be taking into consideration. Uh,
green buttons for call to actions, et cetera, right?
Okay. And they're using emojis really great for U G C content.
So let's, uh, now that we've got those ideas in our mind,
let's take a look at our shot list. So I'll just, uh,
minimize this and
let me just make that bigger, right? So
If we zoom in here,
we can see that we've got multiple different scroll stoppers and we have
in our shot list in our scripting,
we've created multiple different scroll stoppers. In fact,
we've actually got 10, which is quite a lot to be honest.
Usually most clients that would only test three or four different scroll
stoppers. But yeah, we, we went ham on this one. This is a really good product.
And um, yeah, it is really great to have more options.
Really, really great to have more options.
So right here we've got three different variations of headlines as you
can see from the different colors.
We've got three signs you need to replace your dog leash. So
right here, three signs you need to replace your dog leash.
Then we've got skull stopper, five to seven,
three reasons you need
three reasons why you need the grip harness.
So this is these three here. So if I just enable that to disable that one,
And then we've got scroll stoppers eight to 10,
which is three signs your dog needs a new dog leash.
Okay, right. So we've got different visual cues.
We are using the same style that we used in
the website with the highlighting and et cetera and the colors.
So we are using the dark gray on the colors for the text and we're using the
oranges for the text.
We're highlighting specific words to draw attention to certain,
certain words as we go through the ad.
And
Yeah, so
when it comes to the scroll stoppers,
what we decided to do is focus on different
visuals, uh, using different emojis,
different visuals like us versus them or
this versus that sort of situation. So for example,
show before and after of a dog walking in front of a car and being pulled away
with a leash versus the grip harness. So if we go to
number one here, scroll stopper number one.
If I just disable those. So right here,
right at the beginning here we've got the dog, the car pulling up,
and we've got three signs you need to replace your dog leash.
We've got a big emoji cross mark and we've got the
emoji check mark.
And right here we can see the dog being choked as it's being pulled in front of
the car. And then right here on the right hand side,
we can see that the owner is able to grab the harness and pull the dog to
safety easily. Okay,
so like that comparison thing is a really good
hot trending thing in social media right now. So these,
these are things to pay attention to when creating your scripting,
creating your ideas for your shots.
Um, okay,
so we've also got three signs you need to replace your dog leash.
Again, it is a a versus thing.
So show a dog being pulled away from a fight with a regular leash versus a dog
being pulled away with a harness. So let's check that one out.
So again, very similar sort of, if I just play this through
Three signs, you need to replace your dog leash,
Right? So again, it's that emotional side.
You don't want your dog to be fighting and you don't wanna have to be
pulling him away and not have control, but on the right hand side,
so on the left hand side, there's no control.
We've got two dogs fighting on the right hand side.
We've got a dog that's actually kind of happy and been pulled away from danger
and it's in a relaxed state. So yeah,
really getting that comparison, that contrast we've even used, um,
desaturation on the negative side of things and kept it saturated on
the positive side of things. So yeah, really good things to consider.
Um, Oh, here's a really great one I think. Uh, where's,
so we've also got some images here that you can put into your shot list just to
kind of give you ideas of like how you want to shoot
things. So you could be looking at ads online and see, oh,
I really like that idea.
Take a screenshot of that and then you can kind of implement that into your ad
and include that in your shot list just to give you a bit of guidance.
So for an example here we've got the grip harness on a blowup
dog, or the idea was actually to have a stuffed animal,
but I think we ended up using a blowup animal
with a choke color. So this is
scroll stopper number seven.
So if I just zoom in here and see number seven here, okay,
so if I just put that one on,
oh no, I believe that might be eight. Sorry,
I made a mistake. There we go. There's the,
if I just move this back here. So
if I just play that
Three sides, your dog,
Oh, I need to disable that one,
Three sides. Your dog needs a new leash,
Right? So we've got a really aggressive dog collar here,
something that's gonna be choking actually may be
causing pain with the dog.
And we're using the visual cue of not an actual dog.
'cause we wouldn't want do that ourselves, put a dog through pain. But
using this blowup doll is kind of a, like an interesting hook.
It likes like what, what the hell is going on here, right? So again,
it's a scroll stopping queue.
It's something that's going to stop the audience from scrolling and they go,
what, what is this? Okay,
so what we can do is then, oh,
we'll come back to the scroll stoppers actually in a little while. So what,
uh,
what we then went on to is like the next five or 10 seconds,
we really focus in on the pain points. Okay?
So right here it says, I had no idea,
but I was walking my dog completely wrong.
These colors are basically choking hazards for your dogs every time your dog
pulls. And I've never wanted to put my pup in pain.
So after doing some research on safer solutions, et cetera,
okay, so we've got three different scenes here that's focusing on a pain point,
really hitting home on the emotions.
So this is really good idea just to get
that emotional connection and keep people viewing,
Especially for this product, especially with dogs. Okay?
So right now I'm just, I'll just play this through so you can see, see what,
what we did here. Um, we're gonna have some different visuals.
We've got like far away visual of a problem, closeup, visuals of a problem,
shocking visuals of a problem, okay? So I'll, I'll just uh,
give you an idea of that.
I had no idea, but I was walking my dogs completely wrong.
Okay? So we've got the actor being pulled across the road with the dog
out of control, just really pulling them.
There's actually a little bit of a comedy effect in this. Also no
Idea that I was walking my dogs completely,
Right? There's something that's relatable.
There's a lot of dog owners out there that are being pulled around, okay? Um,
and then straight on these colors are basically,
what is it?
These colors are basically choking hazards for your dog,
Right? So we've got the closeup of the dog being choked,
Colors are based,
And then we've got a closeup of the owner being choked. Like,
how would you like it if this felt on, like if, how would you,
you feel if you was being pulled and choked all of the time,
you wouldn't enjoy this. So yeah, and again,
if you see we're using different highlighting on the text here,
we've got choking hazards dogs,
we here these collars with a,
we've got an emoji pointing the arrow down at the collar,
really driving the focus of what we want the viewer to be looking at.
Collars, pointing down, choking hazards, dogs,
visuals, emojis, painful emoji faces, right?
And then every time your dog pulls,
we've got another view of the dog being pulled. Again,
I never wanna put my pup in paint,
Okay? So not only are we using the visual side of things,
but we're also using the audio side of things. If you listen carefully,
we've got like solemn somber music that like
takes you into a place of emotion almost that makes you thinking like,
almost like contemplative music. So
Three sides, your dog needs a new leash. I had no idea,
but I was walking my dogs completely wrong.
These collars are basically choking hazards for your dogs every time your dog
pulls. I never wanna put my,
Again this emoji big egg mark, stop doing this,
stop doing this. And we've got that music.
And now we are gonna switch gears now and we are gonna move on to like
the solution of this problem.
We are going to flip the music change that we're gonna change the
approach of the emojis. We're gonna give more positive messaging with our,
with our captions. So right here,
hang on. Alright.
Okay, so we've got here,
I came across the grip harness and besides the thousands of reviews,
it looked perfect for my peachy. Okay?
So after doing some research on safer solutions, I came across the grip harness,
Right? So I want you to pay attention to the visuals that we've used here.
So not only have we
focused on certain things, like,
So after doing
So, after doing research,
Doing some research on safer solu,
Safer solutions.
So we've been focusing on safer solutions after doing research
we've used
Okay,
Uh, emojis that a bit more happier,
a bit more inviting.
We're also shown without even saying it,
we've shown how easy,
how easy this product is to put on the dog,
how relaxed the dog is looking,
Research on safer solution,
How easy that was to clip on
Since I came across the grip harness. And besides the thousands of,
We reaffirmed that twice. Okay?
So not only are we saying in the v in the audio,
in the vo, the voiceover and the captions one message,
but we're also showing more messaging in our,
in what we've shot.
So we've been very specific with what we're showing our audience right now.
So within the first 15 seconds,
we have come up with a product. Now we've come up with problems,
we've got hooks that have got Comparisons,
this versus this,
this bad situation versus this good situation, setting the product up for
like something that's really positive for your, for your dog.
And then we've gone through all the, the pain points, the sad somber,
emotional side of things.
We've really gripped 'em with the emotion side and something that they can
connect to.
And then we've hit them hard with after come up after
doing research and thousands of positive reviews, et cetera,
and shown them how easy it is to put on with a visual showing 'em how easy,
how happy their dogs are without even saying anything, right?
It's really, really smart specific
way of approaching this ad.
The thousands of reviews. It looked perfect for my peachy
Right in the past right here.
I want to go more over like the,
the reasoning behind why we've got stars here.
In the past we had different ads where we might have had like
reviews popping up onto the screen,
but this is user generated content, right?
You want to think of this ad as something that someone may have made on their
phone at home. So we are just using very simple emojis,
very simple captioning that's almost looks native to Instagram, TikTok,
Facebook, et cetera, right? And
we want to keep it simple but keep it direct.
We really want to make sure that our message is showing exactly what we want
our viewer to understand. And
Yeah,
So let's go through reviews looked
Perfect for my peachy.
Now we've, we just repeated the same shot here.
We've got the pain point
and now we've just done like another comparison with
It's the thousands of reviews. It looked perfect for my peach,
Nice, easily walking, relaxed again.
We're now going to the slip-on.
So we've covered the fact that now the dog is more relaxed.
We've covered the fact that the owner is more relaxed.
We've shown how happy the dog is.
We've really connected to the emotional side of things now.
And now we can go onto the extra, um,
benefits and features of the product. By now,
maybe the audience or the viewer may have clicked through
and thought, hell yeah,
this is exactly what I need and clicked through on the link.
Or they might have just like swiped on buy or lost interest at this point we
never know, but those people who are really interested in, in this ad,
we can now hit home and say, okay,
these are the real features and benefits of this product. Okay,
So now I can just slip it on in seconds is amazing no more.
Okay? And then we're very specific with the shots that we've taken.
We've got a shot of both the uh,
how easy and relaxed the dog and the owner are as we're putting on the harness.
We've got closeups of actually clipping the harness and how easy
that is with a happy smiley dog, right? And then
again,
closeups of the harness itself harnesses in full view.
The dog is looking happy and it's super easy to attach the leash to the harness.
Kiss
Is amazing. No
Big old smiles from our, from our owner
Or needing to chase her around for a walk.
She even walks better with it and is a lot easier to manage even if she gets
distracted,
Right? So now we are hitting home on that super easy walks, dog is relaxed,
owner is relaxed and they're having lots of fun. Great, right?
So now it's really durable and secure so
It's really durable and secure.
So now we're focusing on the handle part of the product and we are then gonna
lead into, we like more pain points.
So we're gonna be danced from this point onwards. We are gonna be looking at
the features and benefits,
but also like dancing between the features and the benefits and the pain points.
Just to kind of reaffirm that there is an issue here with
the old style of walking the dog with the,
the choke collar compared to the,
the product here, the grip harness, right? So again, it comes off with
Ease,
Comes off with ease. The
Grip harness I'm able to act,
We've reaffirmed the product name
Comes off with ease with the grip harness,
Okay?
I'm able to actually pull her away from anything.
So we've shown the benefit but we've also showing the pain point here, right?
So the benefit is, is we can pull them away from danger cars,
et cetera. This could be um, walking across the road where there's a,
a stop sign, a busy highway or something. Yeah,
could be many multiple different things, kids walking by,
kids ride riding by on their bikes, quickly pull the dog out the way, et cetera.
So we can get really creative with this,
but also show the positive side of the product
Her
And then again versus yanking on the leash. On a leash. Yes,
we was quite lucky with these shots because we've got a couple of dogs that
they're not actually fighting, they're just playing.
But luckily we got those no unexpectedly we got those shots
where they kind of had their teeth showing and stuff. So we,
we use this in our ad and again, we've got the big, if we see this,
we've got the emojis here and again we're focused on specific words,
yanking neck leash, right?
Things that we want them to be focusing on, see the teeth,
see that it's really difficult to control the dog.
But right before that we showed them how easy it was to save our
dog from danger. Okay? So like I said, with dancing between the,
the positives and the negatives, the benefits, the features and the pain points,
Danger versus yanking her neck on a leash. This is a lot,
A lot safer. We got the positive emoji tick there, the check mark
Take and gives me peace of mind during walks.
Okay? And now we're just talking about like
Has her name and
The name, the phone number, et cetera she
Ever were to get lost. It's ref.
And then we've got the reflective side of things.
Reflective whenever I walk her at night,
I'm never going back to a basic leash again.
Again, just reaffirming. We're never going back to that basic leash. And again,
big x mark there, right?
We could have even desaturated this a little bit.
I think I may have desaturate desaturated it a little touch,
but I think it was more focusing on the big red X and basic
leash, et cetera. And then thrown in the trash trashcan.
It's kind of shows exactly what we need it to see. Like to show the
Leash again, what's most important is peaches. Loves it.
Okay? And then we've got happy smiley dog product in full view,
happy smiley owner. And then thank you Grip harness.
Thank you
Grip harness.
And again, we've used, like I said before on the website,
we've got the green call to action here.
We've got the keeping it very simple, very basic.
We have got different various call to action assets
that you can use like um, templates and whatever.
But right here we just kept it very simple, simple
call to action button and the logo in the middle and then the product on a pure
white background just because we're going with the look and feel of their
website. So yeah,
we've gone through the entire ad and
we can like, now these captions here,
if you pay attention to ads at the moment,
they're doing a lot of highlighting things like especially the animated
highlighting words where it's going word by word or single words popping up onto
the screen. That's really great for U G C content right now. Just single words,
really fast, sequential single words. Um, but yeah, we,
because this is like
an emotional ad and something like we really wanna focus not
just,
we don't wanna be blasting people with loads of information really quick like
overstimulating with this type of product,
but keep it nice and emotional. Highlight specific words,
keep it kind of relative to the brand.
But mostly we are focused on keeping it looking like it's a user generated
content. Something that is native to social media platforms. Okay?
Super simple, super effective,
super effective structure, okay?
And all throughout the video we've got closeups, we've got
wide shots of crossing the roads, um,
gen,
we've made sure that we've got shots of the dogs happy
and excited again with the owner,
happy and excited and enjoying the product.
So now we've got that ad sequence
again, pain points,
reaffirm the benefits and features and then go over the remaining benefits and
features and kind of dance between the pain points and benefits and features
until the call to action in the middle here,
we could have added another call to action, right? Just,
just as we've introduced the product.
Like right here I came,
I came across the grip harness with these reviews, it was amazing, et cetera.
Perfect for my peachy.
We could have had another call to action right here.
That's another like thing that you could use just to,
because like around midpoint of the ad,
people might be dropping off and not want to watch the entire ad.
A lot of people have short attention spans these days.
It's maybe not down to your ad or be engaging or whatever.
It could simply be down to the audience's attention span.
So having a call to action in the middle here is actually quite effective.
But we used right here just reaffirming the actual
grip harness name, okay? The, the brand name.
We really wanted to reaffirm that brand name throughout and keep it
reaffirming the pain points and reaffirming to connect to the emotional side of
things.
Now we've got this ad structure and we have all these different hooks and
well scroll stoppers. Now how can we use these different scroll stoppers?
What is the benefit of having all these different scroll stoppers? Well,
what we wanna do is when we're running our ads, we want to
test all of these different scroll stoppers,
like funnel a little bit of money into these different variations of the ad
and then check out the analytics and figure out which ads are
performing better than others.
Which ads are keeping retention past a certain point past
the hook, past the 10, 15 second mark, et cetera.
So these hooks are going to define whether
or not someone is going to stop and watch your ad or even continue to watch
the ad.
So you this hook right here with the spiky dog
color going into an inflatable dog that could be enough to be like, whoa,
what is this? And hit someone really in the heart and be like, no, no,
this is wrong. You should never, ever have a dog collar like this.
And then we come up with a solution and then like they might force them or
get them to watch most of the ad.
It could be the defining thing between an ad being successful
or unsuccess unsuccessful. So yeah,
we went ham on the scroll stoppers,
we've got 10 different versions we could probably added more.
We might even add more in the future, but when we're creating different ads,
et cetera. But yeah, we figure out which are the most,
the better performing ads, maybe the top four or five,
then put more money into those and maybe even refine that down to the top two
ads.
And then put most of our attention in scaling those top two ads that are getting
more retention, more comments, more click-through rates.
Ultimately that's what we're looking for. We're looking for click-through rates,
sales signups, et cetera.
Whatever it is that you need people to do for this
ad. Okay. So yeah,
I hope that makes sense and I hope this helped you
understand what U g C content is all about. Um,
we can keep things really super simple.
We can really strip this down to like 20 seconds or so if we wanted to.
Um, we didn't have to go so ham on this,
so we could have different variations of this ad. Drop it down to 20 seconds,
have different creators. Like we right here,
we've used a voiceover machine's. Completely wrong these,
so automatic voiceover. We used a, a site called Mic Monster.
Um,
you can go on there and it's just a really good automated vo um,
website that, yeah, you just type in what you want and it will just generate,
you can pick between different voices, male voices, female voices,
different emotion to the voice, et cetera. So it's,
that's a really good thing to use. But then we also use different creatives,
actual people talking to the camera. Um,
you could use green screen right here,
like you could have someone in the bottom, bottom corner here talking.
You see that a lot on social media. So yeah, just do a lot of research,
see what's happening in your niche area,
see what ads are really working well for like those people or what is really
popular, what's getting a lot of views and attention.
And then start implementing them into your ideas.
Your U G C I like ideas when you're creating your scripts and your shot list
and ultimately going out and filming and creating your ad in
post-production. So yeah, I hope this has helped guys and uh,
I'll see you in the next tutorial. Peace.